# VINCENT JOHN CAGAY

me@vjcagay.com · www.linkedin.com/in/vjcagay · www.github.com/vjcagay +81 070 4428 1348 · TŌKYŌ, JAPAN

#### PROFTI F

I am an engineer who is highly driven when doing projects with good design (visually and friendly), architecture, and good direction. I helped build scalable web apps from internal tools to products that serves millions of users. Mainly working on front-end, I have lots of experience migrating legacy systems to modern architectures.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

VIRTUSIZE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, FULL-TIME) | TOKYO, JP | 2019 - PRESENT

- 1. Rewrite and maintain the phone size comparison tool for Docomo's online shop (iPhones and Android devices) showing the width, height, and thickness, to help customers visualize the sizes of the device they are wanting to buy. Setup continuous integration for the deployment of this tool to production.
- 2. Write and maintain components for Virtusize Design System, which is used by multiple Virtusize applications, including the company's core product
- 3. Rewrite and maintain Virtusize's core product: a tool to help users visualize and choose the perfect size of the garment (and accessories) they want to buy, based on their body size, or an existing item they possess. This tool is embedded into online shops (mainly fashion brands). Works on the frontend side of the product. Also helps in integrating the product into current and new client's online shops.

ASURION K.K. SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, CONTRACT) | TOKYO, JP | 2018 - 2019

- Maintain the application used by customer service representatives in handling customer queries for mobile device insurance (e.g. warranties, factory defects). Rearchitect the application front-end to solve very hard to fix bugs (especially Internet Explorer-related) and make it easier to add more features and development during the takeover from old-school JavaScript to modern TypeScript.
- 2. Write UI components that can be imported and used for building several products with specific use-cases (e.g. text fields, date pickers, steppers, alert messages)
- 3. Help build an application for handling device insurance designed to be used by several insurance companies

SKYARCH NETWORKS SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, CONTRACT) | TOKYO, JP | 2016 - 2018

- 1. Rewrite the company's legacy error reporting system from scratch with newer technologies and better software practices.
  - Rewrite the user interface from scratch enabling better user experience with Vue and TypeScript
  - Use Apollo to access GraphQL backend API
  - Deploy code to production using AWS CodeCommit, CloudFront, Code Pipeline
  - · Maintain the backend written in Python
  - · Handle real-time notifications with Socket.IO
- 2. Implement the SSO for the company's internal applications
  - · Write the user interface with React and TypeScript
  - · Maintain the backend written in Node
  - · Manage employee data with AWS Lambda, RDS, and Cognito
  - Push front-end code to AWS S3
- 3. Develop a mobile application for a company client that takes images and upload into their servers
  - · Write the application in React-Native and TypeScript
  - · Handle users via AWS Cognito
  - · Upload the images to AWS S3

INFOR PSSC SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONT-END, FULL-TIME) | MANILA, PH | 2015 - 2016

Work on Rhythm, an e-commerce platform and one of the company's core products

- · Write the widgets the client can customize to fit with their business
- · Rewrite the Search Widget from scratch to fix all bugs and issues
- · Write widgets in Backbone/Marionette, WebPack, SASS

SCHOOL IMPROVEMENT NETWORK SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FULL-STACK, FULL-TIME) | CEBU, PH | 2013 - 2015

- 1. Migrate Edivate (formerly named PD360) front-end from Flash to JavaScript
  - · Write the user interface with Backbone/Marionette, Require, and LESS
  - Contribute to UI/UX decisions in re/implementing new and existing features

#### 2. Also:

- · Rewrite Edivate's backend services from ColdFusion to Node
- · Write Node micro-service for other products and deploy in Docker containers
- Write internal tool for providing graphical UI to Docker in React and Electron
- · Mentor the interns

ADVANZWEB WEB DEVELOPER (FULL-STACK, FULL-TIME) | CEBU, PH | 2013

Implement some of the requested features of EPX2, a soccer player development platform.

- Build spider graphs for player's current ability levels with Raphaël.js
- Write EXP2's mobile version separately (Browsers did not yet support responsive CSS)

#### **EDUCATION**

STI COLLEGE CEBU B.S. INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | CEBU, PH 2013

#### SKILLS

```
JAVASCRIPT Node · TypeScript · Vue · React · React · React · Flux · WebPack · SASS/LESS/CSS-in-JS

AWS AppSync · Cognito · Lambda · CodePipeline · CodeCommit · S3 · CloudFront · RDS

DATABASES MySQL · PostreSQL · MongoDB · GraphQL

CI CircleCI · Travis CI · Jenkins

OTHER Git · Docker · Vagrant · Linux · GitHub · GitLab · JIRA · Unit Testing
```

#### LANGUAGES

ENGLISH fluent
FILIPINO fluent
CEBUANO native
JAPANESE basic

#### **INTERESTS**

TYPOGRAPHY and UI/UX
MOBILE and PROGRESSIVE WEB APPS, WEBASSEMBLY
WEB ANIMATION and ACCESSIBILITY
SWIFT / IOS DEVELOPMENT

## CURRENTLY LEARNING / AIMING TO LEARN

JAPANESE

MACHINE LEARNING, A.I.PHOTOGRAPHY, and COMPUTER VISION